We're going to talk about libraries and modules.
So I've been using a few modules here and there.
You've seen me import a few things, date time, random.
There was a library that helped me do a live reloading
of my modules.
And that's just the thing about Python.
The language was designed to be batteries included.
It has a rich and versatile standard library, which
is immediately available.
I didn't have to download or install anything external.
It just comes with the interpreter.
And many people believe that this
has given the Python language a head start in a lot of cases.
It's really helped vault Python to be the popular tool
that it is today.
So let's take a look at some of those helpful packages
in the standard library.
One of the downsides of the standard library
is that it's really optimized for having a rich feature
set.
And it's also optimized for backwards compatibility.
So as the library has the Python language grows.
For the most part, they try to maintain
as much backwards compatibility as possible.
That means that some of the included libraries
are a little bit hard to use.
But it's really easy to install external libraries as well.
Some of the commonly used features of the standard library
sits, S-Y-S, the provide system specific parameters
and functions.
OS has a lot of methods available for working
with the operating system interface.
And there's a great OS path submodule that
helps us handle files on the file path.
Math gives us a lot of advanced math functions
and JSON.
Helps us as an easy-to-use JSON parser and encoder.
Python even gives you a lot of other built-in libraries,
like database access, logging, internet protocols, multimedia.
There's a debugger.
And there are libraries for extending Python itself.
Later, after this class, you can look at this link
for the full list of standard libraries.
And you'll see this guide from docs.python.org.
So the language library.
And it'll show you all of the bump up that font size there.
It'll show you all everything that's available
on the standard library.
So a very quick tour.
And as you can see, there's a lot of stuff here.
So I mean, you can see there's quite a bit more to scroll through.
But if you're not sure, if you're not sure
if something is included with the Python language,
this is a good place to look.